<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Google Search Central Blog</title>
  <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/</link>
  <description>Official news for web professionals about Google Search, related products, and events.</description>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live Bangkok 2024</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/search-central-live-bangkok-2024</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/search-central-live-bangkok-2024</guid>
    <description>
      We're coming back to Thailand with Search Central Live! As mentioned in our blog post about our APAC plans for SCL, we now have a date and a site where you can sign up for a chance to secure your spot at Search Central Live Bangkok 2024.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Adding markup support for organization-level return policies</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/structured-data-return-policies</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/structured-data-return-policies</guid>
    <description>
      We're adding support for return policies at the organization level, which means you'll
      be able to specify a general return policy for your business instead of having to define one
      for each individual product you sell.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 4 Jun 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>We're on LinkedIn (finally)</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/linkedin-we-are-here</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/linkedin-we-are-here</guid>
    <description>
      The Google Search Central LinkedIn channel is (finally) here!
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 4 Jun 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Mobile-indexing-vLast-final-final.doc</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/mobile-indexing-vlast-final-final.doc</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/06/mobile-indexing-vlast-final-final.doc</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        The last step of our migration to a mobile-first index
        will soon be complete: the small set of sites we've still been crawling with desktop Googlebot
        will be crawled with mobile Googlebot after July 5, 2024.
        Most websites do not need to do anything!
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 3 Jun 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live 2024 is coming back to the APAC region</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/05/search-central-live-jakarta-apac-2024</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/05/search-central-live-jakarta-apac-2024</guid>
    <description>
    Search Central Live is coming back to the Asia Pacific region, bringing you insights from Google Search, fun networking opportunity, and more! This year we're aiming to visit Indonesia, Malaysia, Taiwan, and Thailand.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Improving Search Console ownership token management</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/04/search-console-ownership-token-management</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/04/search-console-ownership-token-management</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        This post discusses an update to Search Console's user and permissions to improve the
        accuracy and reflect the actual state of unused ownership tokens.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live 2024 in Warsaw, Poland</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/search-central-live-poland-2024</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/search-central-live-poland-2024</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        We're excited to announce a Search Central Live event in Warsaw, Poland on April 24, 2024.
        <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/events/search-central-live">Search Central Live</a>
        is our global Google Search event series specifically for site owners, publishers, and SEOs.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>What web creators should know about our March 2024 core update and new spam policies</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/core-update-spam-policies</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/core-update-spam-policies</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        <p>
          Today we <a href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-update-march-2024" class="external-link">announced</a>
          the March 2024 core update. This is designed to improve the quality of Search by showing less
          content that feels like it was made to attract clicks, and more content that people find useful.
          We also shared that we have new <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/essentials/spam-policies">spam policies</a>
          to better handle the practices that can negatively impact Google's search results. In this post,
          we'll go into more detail for creators about both the update and the spam policies.
        </p>
      ]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live 2024 in Bucharest, Romania</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/search-central-live-romania-2024</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/03/search-central-live-romania-2024</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        We're excited to announce a Search Central Live event in Bucharest, Romania on April 4, 2024.
        <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/events/search-central-live">Search Central Live</a>
        is our global Google Search event series specifically for site owners, publishers, and SEOs.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Adding structured data support for Product Variants</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/product-variants</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/product-variants</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        In 2022, Google <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2022/09/merchant-listings">expanded support for Product structured data</a>, enabling enhanced product experiences in Google Search.
        Then, in 2023 we <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/04/shipping-and-returns-information">added support for shipping and returns structured data</a>.
        Today, we are <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/appearance/structured-data/product-variants">adding structured data support for Product variants</a>, allowing merchants to easily show more variations of the products they sell, and show shoppers more relevant, helpful results.
        Providing variant structured data will also complement and enhance <a href="https://support.google.com/merchants/answer/7439882" class="external-link">merchant center feeds</a>, including <a href="https://support.google.com/merchants/answer/7538732" class="external-link">automated feeds</a>.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Search experiences in EEA: Rich results, aggregator units, and refinement chips</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-experiences-in-eea</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-experiences-in-eea</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        Following our latest <a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/an-update-on-our-preparations-for-the-dma/" class="external-link">update on our preparations for the DMA</a>
        (Digital Markets Act), we're sharing more details about what publishers can expect to see in
        regards to new search results in <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/statistics-explained/index.php?title=Glossary:European_Economic_Area_(EEA)" class="external-link">European Economic Area</a>
        (EEA) countries, and how they can express interest in these experiences.
        </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The SEO Starter Guide got a makeover</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/ssg-gets-a-makeover</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/ssg-gets-a-makeover</guid>
    <description>
      Today we're publishing a refreshed, more pocket-sized version of the SEO Starter Guide with
      a better focus on a starter audience and the topics we think a person who's just dipping
      their toes in SEO should focus on and why.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 2 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Announcing Search Central Live Argentina</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-central-live-argentina</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-central-live-argentina</guid>
    <description>
    We're excited to announce that Search Central Live is coming to Buenos Aires on March 5, 2024. Following successful events throughout
    the world last year, we're continuing our mission to help website owners to enhance their site's performance in Google Search.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 1 Feb 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live is returning to Brazil</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-central-live-sao-paulo-2024</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2024/02/search-central-live-sao-paulo-2024</guid>
    <description>
    We're excited to announce that Search Central Live is returning to São Paulo on February 29, 2024. Following our successful events
    last year, we're continuing our mission to help Brazilian businesses enhance their site's performance in Google Search.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 1 Feb 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>This is over</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/definitely-not-ai-generated-post</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/definitely-not-ai-generated-post</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
        I'm sure you're all wondering why we have gathered you here today. That's right: it's the
        end of year blog post in which we go over what happened in 2023 on Google Search Central,
        and have some fun along the way!
        </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Video mode now only show pages where video is the main content</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/video-is-the-main-content</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/video-is-the-main-content</guid>
    <description>
      Earlier this year, we made a change to only show video thumbnails next to results on the main
      Google Search results page when the video is the main content of a page. Today, we're
      extending this change to search results in Video mode to
      better connect users with the video content they're looking for (rather than having to comb
      through a page to find that video). This change will start rolling out today, and it could take
      up to a week to complete.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Adding markup support for vacation rentals</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/hello-vacation-rentals</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/12/hello-vacation-rentals</guid>
    <description>
      Vacation rentals on Google make it easier for travelers to discover the best lodging options,
      whether they're searching for a cozy cabin or a house that sleeps ten. Today, we're announcing a
      new and simpler way for vacation rental integration partners to provide listing data to Google.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Expanding markup support for Organization details, including Logo structured data</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/introducing-organization-markup</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/introducing-organization-markup</guid>
    <description>
      Since 2013, Google has supported logo structured data, which recognizes two Organization
      fields: logo and url. Today we're expanding our support for organizational information by
      extracting additional administrative data such as name, address, contact information, and
      various business identifiers. You can continue to provide the logo and url fields to specify
      which image we use as your logo in Google search results.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New in structured data: discussion forum and profile page markup</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/discussion-and-profile-markup</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/discussion-and-profile-markup</guid>
    <description>
      Today we're announcing support for profile page and discussion forum structured data for use
      in Google Search, including new reports in Search Console. This markup works with Google
      Search features that are designed to show first-person perspectives from social media
      platforms, forums, and other communities.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Upcoming deprecation of Crawl Rate Limiter Tool in Search Console</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/sc-crawl-limiter-byebye</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/sc-crawl-limiter-byebye</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
      The crawl rate limiter tool in Search Console is being deprecated on Jan 8th, 2024. This tool
      has been
      <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2008/12/more-control-of-googlebots-crawl-rate">available for over a decade</a>,
      but with the improvements we've made to our crawling logic and other tools available to
      publishers, its usefulness has dissipated.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Quality Raters Guidelines update</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/search-quality-rater-guidelines-update</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/search-quality-rater-guidelines-update</guid>
    <description>
      As of November 16, Google's Search Quality Rater Guidelines have been updated to simplify our guidelines.
      As a reminder, these guidelines are what are used by our search raters to help evaluate the performance
      of our various search ranking systems, and their ratings don't directly influence ranking.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>List your courses with new course info structured data</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/new-course-info-markup</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/new-course-info-markup</guid>
    <description>
      As people continue to search for courses on Google, the desire for more detailed course
      information has grown. Today, we are announcing a new set of recommendations to provide
      course structured data to Google. Publishers now have the opportunity to surface supplemental
      course information on Google Search by providing detailed information like pricing, educational
      level, ratings, and length with structured data. This data can appear in the course info rich
      result, which is a new carousel feature in Google Search that helps learners discover and compare
      courses that fit their unique needs.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A Q&amp;A on Google Search updates</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/q-and-a-on-search-updates</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/q-and-a-on-search-updates</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[
      Google Search regularly updates our search ranking systems to ensure we're showing the most
      relevant, helpful content that we can. We've had a series of notable updates we've shared about
      in the past few weeks, and we have two for this month. Given this, it's a good time to share some
      reminders in a Q&A format about how we do updates, why we share about them, and what (if anything)
      creators need to consider when one happens.
    ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 2 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live Taipei 2023</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/search-central-live-taipei-2023</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/11/search-central-live-taipei-2023</guid>
    <description>
      We're excited to announce that Search Central Live is coming back to Taipei for the first time ever on December 6. As usual, the event is hosted by the Google
      Search team and we're looking forward to bringing together the community to learn, share, and
      network.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 2 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Mobile-first indexing has landed</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/mobile-first-is-here</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/mobile-first-is-here</guid>
    <description>
      We're delighted to announce that the trek to Mobile First Indexing is now complete.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live Singapore 2023</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/search-central-live-singapore-2023</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/search-central-live-singapore-2023</guid>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p>
      We're excited to announce that
      <a href="https://rsvp.withgoogle.com/events/search-central-live-singapore-2023" class="external-link">Search Central Live Singapore</a>
      is coming back this year again on November 22. As usual, the event is hosted by the Google
      Search team and we're looking forward to bringing together the community to learn, share, and
      network.
      </p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Vehicle listings structured data for car dealerships</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/vehicle-listings-structured-data</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/vehicle-listings-structured-data</guid>
    <description>
      Google Search will start supporting vehicle listings markup, a new way to appear in  vehicle listings on Google.
      It now has its own Search Console Rich result report and is supported in the testing tool.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>October 2023 Spam Update</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/october-2023-spam-update</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/10/october-2023-spam-update</guid>
    <description>
      We're releasing an update to our spam detections systems today that will improve our coverage
      in many languages and spam types.
    </description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Search Central Live Zurich is back!</title>
    <link>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/09/search-central-live-zurich</link>
    <guid>https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2023/09/search-central-live-zurich</guid>
    <description>
      We're very excited to announce that Search Central Live is coming back to Zurich on Tuesday, October 24th, 2023!
      After our last Search Central Live event in Zurich in December 2019, we're back in town for more presentations, Q&amp;A and networking!
    </description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
